<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Lab Notes - Epistemic Moral Beliefs Project</title>
<link>https://rameliaz.github.io/labnotes-emb/</link>
<atom:link href="https://rameliaz.github.io/labnotes-emb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description></description>
<generator>quarto-1.8.14</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 12:08:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Development of Ideas</title>
  <dc:creator>Amelia Zein</dc:creator>
  <link>https://rameliaz.github.io/labnotes-emb/posts/development-of-ideas/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<section id="some-random-ideas-that-i-have-in-mind-at-the-moment-those-ideas-were-written" class="level1">
<h1>Some random ideas that I have in mind at the moment those ideas were written</h1>
<p><strong>[Entry - Tuesday, 22.07.2025]</strong> - After doing a theory building, start small by simulating one moral pair, i.e., “reason/rationality” vs.&nbsp;“competent authority” by assuming that the outcomes (absolutist vs relativist vs tolerant) emerge as a dynamic interaction between a teacher and students in a classroom setting. Parameters can be based on the wealth of evidence regarding the role of testimony in belief/knowledge acquisition. - I really need to build arguments that <em>truth-seeking process</em> which encapsulates the epistemic moral beliefs is a dyadic situation, where at least two agents interact with each others. Epistemic behaviors that are considered “moral” can be: 1) the individual’s moral framework; 2) other agents’ or appraisers’ moral framework, or 3) the social context surrounding the actions/behaviors.</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>learning</category>
  <category>ideas</category>
  <category>journal</category>
  <guid>https://rameliaz.github.io/labnotes-emb/posts/development-of-ideas/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 12:08:52 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://rameliaz.github.io/labnotes-emb/posts/development-of-ideas" medium="image"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Marlene Batzke’s Talk on Agent-Based Modeling</title>
  <dc:creator>Amelia Zein</dc:creator>
  <link>https://rameliaz.github.io/labnotes-emb/posts/marlene-batzke-talk/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 





<section id="my-notes-from-the-talk" class="level1">
<h1>My notes from the talk</h1>
<ol type="1">
<li>ABM allows us to test theoretical assumptions on a micro (individual) and macro (group) level — even the simplest assumptions can be super hard to predict.</li>
<li>Allowing us to predict a system on a macro level as well as individual elements/roles on that macro level.</li>
<li>Models don’t need to be perfect, at least it serves the function (being useful).</li>
<li>Start with very simple assumptions, therefore simple parameters. More parameters make models overfitting.</li>
<li>People can basically refine the model parameters following up the simulation results and redo the simulations with updated parameters. But make sure to take notes on everything!</li>
<li>We could do experiments to simulate the theories under different scenarios —- Perfect for my epistemic moral beliefs project where I can simulate the predictions in a classroom setting!!!!</li>
<li>Combining ABM with experiments data is perfectly possible, either use experimental results to create model parameters, or use simulation results to generate more hypotheses, making sense of conflicting experimental results.</li>
<li>More parameters (assumptions) we put in the model would make the models unnecessarily complex. Start simple!</li>
<li>In specifying the parameters we do and do not want to be super sure/specific about the accuracy or these parameters – most importantly that we need to be sure that these assumptions can be tested. In this sense, we believe that the parameters we test theoretically vary in the population.</li>
<li>What defines a good model is actually <strong>consistency</strong> of the pattern that we’d like to predict. Don’t expect we have clean indicators/indices to evaluate the models – as in statistical models. Even statistical models we use regularly to test hypotheses are “true” under a ton of assumptions that we unconsciously ignore.</li>
</ol>
<p>Example that she gave in the belief polarization project she is working on… Coherence – is defined as a fit with other beliefs depending on the belief system Belief system – is defined as correlation matrices of beliefs but needs to be subjective. To account for subjectivity, she used correlation class analysis (CCA)</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>learning</category>
  <guid>https://rameliaz.github.io/labnotes-emb/posts/marlene-batzke-talk/</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://rameliaz.github.io/labnotes-emb/posts/marlene-batzke-talk" medium="image"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
